Finding aid to the Department of Economics Records CA.MS.00128
Smith College Archives
Department of Economics Records
1934-1996
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Dept. of Economics.
CA.MS.00128
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
This collection contains newspaper and magazine articles, materials for prospective majors, news releases, black and white photographs, class notes, course syllabi, and mid-year and final exam questions.
Biographical / Historical
The Economics Department at Smith College began as the Economics and Sociology Department from the 1894-95 to the 1897-98 academic year. During the 1898-99 academic year it became the Economics Department until 1900-01 when it returned to being called the Economics and Sociology Department. In 1937, the Economics and Sociology Department was separated into individual departments.
Scope and Contents
The Economics Department records contain materials describing the department's courses, clubs, and activities. Types of materials include newspaper and magazine articles about certain classes and a student stock exchange project called ECCLYCO, a student's lecture notes, studies conducted by the department, course syllabi, mid-year and final exam questions, and black and white photographs of faculty and students.
Related Material
Researchers should also view:
RG 42. Faculty
90A-186 Department chair files, 1970-1987 [unprocessed/portions restricted]
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Economics Department records were created by the department and its students and transferred/donated to the College Archives.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Smith College. Dept. of Economics.
- Classes- magazine article, photograph, 1947? (Box 1145, Folder 1)
- Clubs- Social Science Club, Economics Club, 1936; 1940 (Box 1145, Folder 2)
- Economics Dept.- general, 1930s-70s; 1996 (Box 1145, Folder 3)
- ECCLYCO- student group, 1945-50 (Box 1145, Folder 4)
- Courses- general, 1950; 1953; 1967; 1970-71 (Box 1145, Folder 5)
- Economics 4a, 6b- student lecture notes, undated (Box 1145, Folder 6)
- Economics 21-45, 1940-57 (Box 1145, Folder 7)
- Economics 110-317, 1946-80 (Box 1145, Folder 8)
- Economics 315, 1943-56 (Box 1145, Folder 9)
- Finance study, 1941 (Box 1145, Folder 10)
- Photographs, 1940s; 1950s; 1980s; 1990 (Box 1145, Folder 11)
- Reading lists, 1934; 1938-39 (Box 1145, Folder 12)
- Time survey, 1934 (Box 1145, Folder 13)